agriculture.vic.gov.au 2019-12-22

# Privacy | Agriculture Victoria

Topics on this page include:

  * Application of this Privacy Statement
  * Personal information
  * Collection of personal information
  * How we collect information
  *     * Surveys
    * Electronic Direct Mail & Newsletter Subscriptions
    * Social Media
    * Online forms
  * Use and disclosure of personal information
  * Access to and correction of personal information
  * Internet user risks
  * Website usage measurement
  * Email addresses
  * Cookies

## Application of this privacy statement

This privacy statement applies only to this department's websites. It is consistent with the department's privacy policy and applies to all activities of the department and its agencies.

This website contains links to other websites which are not part of the department. This privacy statement does not apply to those websites.

The department's privacy policy is available from the Privacy Officer.

### Privacy Officer

Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions  
GPO Box 4509  
Melbourne, VIC, 3001, AUS  
 **Email** : [privacy@ecodev.vic.gov.au](mailto:privacy@ecodev.vic.gov.au)

##  _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic): Personal information

In this privacy statement the term 'personal information' has the meaning provided in section 3 of the _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic).

Personal information is information or an opinion that is recorded in any form, whether true or not, about an individual whose identity is apparent or can reasonably be ascertained.

This Act is the legislation that regulates our collection and handling of personal information.

Detailed information about the Act is available at the [Office of the Victorian Information Commissioner](https://ovic.vic.gov.au/).

## Collection of personal information

It is intended that this website can be used anonymously. However, for some functions, the collection of personal information is necessary or unavoidable. You will know if the department is collecting personal information from you because you will be requested to provide it.

There are two exceptions to this:

  1. When someone else provides the department with your personal information. The department cannot prevent this. However, you are entitled to access and to correct any personal information about you collected by the department
  2. When the department collects website visitation statistics using a web analytics service.

The statistics in No. 2 may qualify as personal information under the _Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014_ (Vic). However, these statistics are not used to identify individual web users.

For further information regarding this, see web usage measurement.

## How we collect information

In accordance with our privacy policy, the department undertakes to treat any personal information provided by you as confidential and only for the purposes indicated. They include but are not limited to the following services.

### Surveys

The department uses both internally built survey software and third-party vendors for the collection, aggregation and analysis of some survey data.

They include, but may not be limited to:

The information you provide is stored in secure data warehouse in either Australia or the United States and is accessed by the department in accordance with each privacy policy.

If you do not want your personal information being stored offshore, you can decline to provide this information by not responding to these surveys

### Electronic Direct Mail (EDM) & Newsletter Subscription

The department uses both internally built mail distribution software and third-party vendors to provide online communication services for some email campaigns and newsletter services.

In subscribing to newsletters, you are providing the department with personal information, which we will not disclose for any other purpose without your consent.

You can unsubscribe at any time and your email address will be moved to a 'do not contact' email database. To do this, click on the unsubscribe link within each email or newsletter type you have previously subscribed to.

Subscriptions supported by third-party vendors only share details to assist with managing delivery, technical issues and the prevention of fraud or security issues. They include but may not be limited to:

Your information will be stored on secure databases which reside in Australia, and the USA. If you do not want your personal information being stored offshore, please do not submit personal information to us.

If you choose to engage with the department via social network channels including Linkedin, Twitter, YouTube, Instagram or Facebook you should be aware of the following:

  * The department only collects information that you voluntarily provide via polls, responses, posts, comments, direct messages and tweets
  * Your social media profile contact details may be used to contact you for feedback or to engage you in conversation. All contact will be made via the channels you choose to participate in
  * Any information you post on social media sites is potentially accessible to anyone else engaging with the same social media.
  * Your individual privacy settings for profiles and accounts on social media networks are your responsibility. The department has no control or jurisdiction over these settings
  * Each social network has inbuilt privacy settings. We strongly recommend that you regularly check and configure the privacy settings for your profiles and accounts to make sure that you know what information you are making available, and to which audience.
  * When you choose to join our social networks and/or participate in any way, some of your personal information may be made visible to others. For example, if you choose to: ‘Like’ a department post, tweet, comment or update; share a link; follow on Twitter; tweet a mention or retweet a message; or join a Facebook Group, your activity may be made visible to others within these network.

Social media account managed by the department include but may not be limited to:

### Online Forms

The department may request information through online forms. The department’s Privacy policy should be made available on the form prior to completion. If completing a form through a third-party provider it’s advised that you examine the Privacy and Security policies. If there is no policy present it is highly recommended you contact the contributing agency or department directly.

If payment services are supported by third-party vendors the department will only shares your details with them to assist:

  * resolution of technical issues; or
  * detection or prevention of fraud or security issues.

## Use and disclosure of personal information

If you provide personal information, the department's privacy policy will regulate its use and disclosure. However, should the department's intended use and disclosure of personal information deviate from the department's general policy, a privacy statement particular to the circumstances will be made available at the time of collection.

Personal information that is collected by the department will be used by, and disclosed to, departmental employees or contractors whose duties require them to use it. Such employees and contractors are required to protect and handle your personal information in accordance with the Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic) and any other applicable legislation regulating the collection, use, disclosure, storage and destruction of personal information.

## Access to and correction of personal information

You may request access to any personal information that the department may have collected about you. Also, you may request correction of your personal information if you can establish that it is not accurate, complete or up-to-date. The Victorian Privacy Commissioner has recommended that the appropriate means to access and correct information held by government departments is pursuant to the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Vic).

The Freedom of Information Officer may be contacted on the details below about access to, and correction of, personal information collected by the Department or for any questions or concerns you may have arising from this privacy statement.

### Freedom of Information Officer

Department of Jobs, Precincts and Regions  
GPO Box 2392  
Melbourne, VIC, 3001, AUS **  
Tel** : (+61 3) 9208 3112  
 **Email** : [foi@ecodev.vic.gov.au](mailto:foi@ecodev.vic.gov.au)

## Internet user risks

The department does not warrant that the functions contained in the site will be uninterrupted or without error. In addition, the department shall not be responsible for the propagation of computer worms, viruses or other harmful components transmitted from this site and other third-party sites.

The department recommends that you ensure that your browser is equipped with updated virus protection software.

## Website usage measurement

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (Google). Google Analytics uses cookies, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser; however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

For further information, please visit the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/privacy.html)

## Email addresses

Email addresses will only be used to respond to specific user queries and will not be kept or used for any purpose other than stated. Email addresses will not be added to a mailing list unless consent is given, nor disclosed to any other party without your knowledge or consent.

## Cookies

This site uses cookies to make your experience of the site easier and more efficient. A cookie is a small data file placed on your hard drive by the web page server. A cookie cannot retrieve any other data from your hard drive, pass on a computer virus, or capture your email address. Note that the cookie will remain on your computer as a record for future visits to this website.

In using cookies the department does not record any personal information or collect names or details of commercial transactions. In addition, the Department does not use cookies as the basis for direct marketing.

You can configure your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, providing you with the opportunity to either accept or reject it. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser or deleting all cookies from your computer if required.
